<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<transcript>
    <metadata>
        <record_id>2008-004</record_id>
        <participants>Kara Swisher; Sheryl Sandberg; Mark Zuckerberg; Barry Sonnenfeld; James Wakim; Arthur; Raul; Male Audience Member;  </participants>
        <type>interview</type>
        <format>video</format>
        <date>2008-08-18</date>
        <source>D6</source>
        <title>D6 Interview With Facebook's Mark Zuckerberg and Sheryl Sandberg</title>
        <url>http://allthingsd.com/video/?video_id=57F1CBF3-231B-4E75-B8B6-8149CBD5A031</url>
        <description>Sheryl Sandberg interviews Mark Zuckerberg during the 2008 D6 conference</description>
    </metadata>
    <contents>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[0:01] Mark Zuckerberg and Sheryl Sandberg.  (Claps once.) Music starts.  Audience applauds.  Zuckerberg and Sandberg enters from stage-left.  Both are carrying a water bottle.  Sandberg is also carrying a big gift bag.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[0:09] Hey.  (Shaking Zuckerberg’s hand.)  Hi.  (Going to and Shaking Sandberg’s hand.)  Hey there.  How’s it going? Have a seat.
All three (3) go to their seats.  Swisher sits down.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[0:15] Ah.</participant>
        <participant name="Sheryl Sandberg">[0:17] So we, uh (pause), we brought you a gift.  (Hands Swisher a purple, princess gift bag.)</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[0:18] A gift!?</participant>
        <participant name="Sheryl Sandberg">[0:19] (Nods.)  We did.  We brought you a gift.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[0:19] And I’m such a princess.  [Yeah, I mean. . . .]  I mean obviously.  (Sandberg hands the bag to Swisher; Swisher takes the bag.)  Oh no, I’m a little frightened.</participant>
        <participant name="Sheryl Sandberg">[0:22] (Inhales.)  We learned (Swisher opening bag) this morning from Barry Diller (sitting down) that we were the (Swisher reaching into bag) princess phone of (Zuckerberg sitting down after Sandberg) our generation.  (Pause.)  And we didn’t (Swisher taking a box out of the bag) know what that was-</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[0:29] Oh my god.  (Looking at the box, princess phone.)  I totally want this.</participant>
        <participant name="Sheryl Sandberg">[0:30] We didn’t know what that was, but was got one (1).</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[0:32] This is a princess phone.  (Looks up at Audience; Audience starts laughing.)  [Yeah.  We did.]</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[0:33] And, um, you know [yeah], since you’ve been so supportive of us we just figured we should get you a gift.</participant>
        <participant name="Sheryl Sandberg">[0:36] Yeah.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[0:37] Thank you so much.  Gosh.</participant>
        <participant name="Sheryl Sandberg">[0:38] And - and you don’t have to write about us anymore.  (Pause.)  [No I think I’ll keep doing that.]  We’re going to put on our desks, right between our desks, and - and then when you have that urge just call us (pause; Zuckerberg smiling and chuckles), talk to us.  Are you that alright?</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[0:45] (Talks over Sandberg.)  You know, what I’m going to do?  I actually don’t have a phone, which is really exciting for me.</participant>
        <participant name="Sheryl Sandberg">[0:47] Perfect.  (Nods.)</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[0:50] (Inhales.)  Secondly (pause), I’m going to ride this puppy till the end.  Just so you know.  (Setting the phone down.)  I’m not giving up now or forever, until you are the biggest (Sandberg laughs) thing in the world or you’re (pause; Zuckerberg smiling) done.  So, um (Audience, Sandberg, and Zuckerberg laughing; Sandberg and Zuckerberg smiling), I think, uh, Steve K [yeah] over there understands that situation.  Yeah, so.</participant>
        <participant name="Sheryl Sandberg">[1:01] Yeah.  We’re looking forward to it.  (Smiling.)</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[1:02] Steve - Steve K- uh, no, no not at all, then.  At one (1) point he was, “You don’t care if we go up or down.”  And, I’m like, “No.  (Shaking her head.)  No (shaking her head), really no.”  Both stories are good (Zuckerberg airy, chuckling) for me.  So, um (shot pause), so let’s get into it.  (Smiling.)  [That’s great.]  Let’s get into the situation here at Facebook.  (Smiling and chuckling.)  First of all I have to say I- I’m- I (quick pause) I promised that I would make this apology.  (Swallows.)  When I started writing about Facebook, when we started All Things D, I wanted to focus in on companies that I thought were really interesting, and one (1)  of the things that’s great about the blogosphere is that you can truly obsess (emphasis) on people, like crazy.  At any time at night I can just [yeah] click away.  Yeah, you know about that.  [We’ve noticed.]  Yeah, I know.  Um, so- a - and you can find people, and it’s really fun that way.  And - and obsession is I- c it’s working really well for me.  So (Audience and Sandberg laugh a little) what’s interesting about it is that sometimes I go a little too far, it’s the middle of the night, eh, you do not sleep when you blog, and you- especially when you have small children, um, and (pause) I - I called you something that I shouldn’t have called you.  It was very funny as far as I was concerned.  I called you “Toddler CEO,” um, it got on 60 Minutes, uh, Lacy Stahl was like, (“impersonation”) “So you called him Toddler (emphasis) CEO?  What does that mean?”  And I was like, “ Oh. (Rolls her eyes.)”  And then I realized it was actually somewhat rude, and I should not have called you that.  Um, I should not call you teenage CEO; I should not call you-  (Zuckerberg laughs.)  You are twenty-three (23), (Zuckerberg smiling and laughing) twenty-four (24)?</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[2:10] I just turned twenty-four (24).  (Big, full, open smile.)</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[2:13] Twenty-four (24) year old CEO.  That’s what I’m going to call you.  (Zuckerberg with a big smile and laughing.)  Uh, so I should call you (slight chuckle) “Toddler CEO,” but it - it was funny.  (Inhales.)  Um, (Zuckerberg smiling; Zuckerberg, Audience, and Swisher laugh) but - but in the middle of the night I should resist that urge.  [Yeah.]  I have a lot of stuff I want to say in the middle of the night that I - that I do edit myself.  [Use the phone.]  Exactly.  I should you use the phone.  [You should use the phone.]  Let’s get into, uh, Facebook.  Now i- i- why- one (1) of the reasons I do write about you so much is I find it a really intriguing and amazing (pause; inhales) company in a very short time (pause) creating and addressing a real problem that people have about (swallows; pause) their online presence, and I do believe (pause) that the reason I do focus on it is ‘cause the promise is huge (emphasis), as far as I am concerned.  You’re- and you’re one (1) of the first companies, along with MySpace and all the other social networking sites, but especially Facebook (inhales) it’s really captures people’s attention of usefulness, utility, (inhales) online presence, and so that’s why I- I’m interested in it.  (Inhales.)  Um, let’s get right into- I’m going to get- I’m going to talk to you, Sheryl about why you left Google, and what you’re (pause) do-ing there.  Um, but u- u- Mark, talk a little bit about- you’ve been written about a lot, you’ve gotten a lot of attention.  What is (pause) Facebook right now?  How do you see it at this moment?  You’ve talked about as a utility, you’ve talked about it as lots of different things.  [Mhm.]  Define Facebook- (pause) J- Jerry was asked to define Yahoo!  (Pause.)  Whether he did so well [yeah] or not - or not.  How do you-
Pause.</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[3:21] (Inhales.)  So, I mean, Facebook is about helping people share information and share themselves.  [okay]  Right?  And for the last four (4) years (pause) what we’ve been doing is just building projects that in different ways (quick pause; inhales) help people share different parts of their personality help them communicate [mhm], um, share parts of their identity with each other, and just open up.  And - and in a way that they’re comfortable with [right], and there are a lot of important pieces to that that make that possible, so giving people complete control over their privacy.  Right?  And - and the information that they put out there.  [mhm]  (Inhales.)  So, and that’s really critical in order to help people share that information.  [mhm]  (Inhales.)  But a lot of it is just building (short pause) different products that are different views on how people live and - and different parts of people’s lives.  So, I mean (pause), early on we built this Photos application.  It was really widely used [right] and, um, and (pause) a - a lot of people used that to just, uh, kind of (pause) get a different view on (pause) on their friends and what other people around them.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[4:08] (Starts talking over Zuckerberg.)  Which people have been doing on the web.  They have been doing a different way.  I mean, it’s not [yeah; pause; nodding] it’s not the newest way.  But what is- what differentiates it?  Wha- what- how do you look at yourself in this special application vs- every single thing on Facebook is replicated somewhere else.  (Zuckerberg nods.)  How do you - how do you imagine that what you’re doing is very different?  If at all-</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[4:25] (Inhales.)  Well, a lot of it is how - howit’s tied together.  (Pause.)  Right, so (pause) people share information (short pause) and share part of themselves so that they can be shared with - with the specific people that they want to see it.  So we - we  have really good privacy settings so that people aren’t sharing with the people that they don’t want to [mhm], but because Facebook is this network and everyone’s friends are there.  (Inhales.)  Um, people can effectively share the - the information, photos, blogs, videos (inhales), different parts of their identity, different information, status updates, whatever they want with people and those people will get it immediately.  [mhm]  Right, so that - that distribution is really important.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[4:56] (Starts talking when Zuckerberg is finishing.)  Who are you looking to as inspiration?  I mean, uh - uh, what was your- everybody has, no- not necessarily mentor, I’m not talking about that, what were you looking at that you saw that you thought, “This is great, but I’m going to change it this (slight emphasis) way.  ‘Cause it’s not- again I don’t call it new thing I don’t find- everyone’s like, “Oh, Facebook.”  All of a sudden it’s the best thing since sliced bread, but (pause) it’s been around (pause) the block people have done this.  What is- what did you look for when you first started?</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[5:19] Well, this trend of people sharing information (short pause) about themselves and just sharing information together online has been something that has been around forever.  Right, I mean, we’ve been building Facebook for - for four (4) years now, but, I mean, even before that when I was in college a little while and high school before that [right] I was still building applications that (pause) that, um (pause), kind of played along with this trend.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[5:39] (Talking over the end of Zuckerberg’s response.)  What - what original companies, was it AOL?  What - what did you look at?  What were you- what informed you, just (quick pause; said with disbelief) several years ago, what was- what were you using that was inspirational to you?</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[5:48] Um (pause; looking up), when- anything on the web.  I mean, I - I think, AOL was - was (starting to smile) definitely something that was interesting to me when I was in high school and-  [Okay; nods.]  Um, I remember (pause) some of my (pause) my early, um (pause), developing days were - were just kind of hacking different things on the AOL platform I - I don’t even know if they called it a platform.  [okay]  But just different people would make stuff in chatrooms and - and things like that all the time, and it was interesting because a lot of my friends in high school [pause; mhm] also learned how to program and grew up (pause) by building thing on top of AOL and that’s kind of interesting because a lot of people now are doing that on top of Facebook Platform.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[6:21] Right, exactly.  Which you’re allowing.  (Zuckerberg nods.)  Stuff like that.  So - so, when you decided to come here you- i- i- explain what it was like to decided, and then I’ll Sheryl something.  (Garbled speech.)  Um, what it was like to come to Silicon Valley.  You have instant attention right away.  (Emphasis; pause.)  That’s a little bit daunting (pause) for anybody and daunting for someone who’s young.  (Pause.)  What was- explain that phenomenon.  It’s happened before a million times in Silicon Valley.  But here you are . . . -</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[6:43] Well actually we started off na - not that quickly.  I mean, I (hesitation) just- I mean, I built Facebook with a couple of my roommates.  (Pause.)  Right?, at Harvard.  [mhm]  And early on we - we actually tapered the growth and kept it in by launching one (1) college at a time. [Pause; mhm.]  And once we go to about thirty (30) colleges (pause) and it was taking off at all of them.  We decided, “Okay this is something that might be worth spending some time in.”  And we decided to invest one (1) (emphasis) summer (pause) in it, and we wanted to get away from Harvard just ‘cause a bunch of us had been there for [and so many people do, yeah] all (slight emphasis) of Freshman year.  Yeah (smiles), well, you know.  And, um-  [At least it would be a good plan, getting away from Harvard.]  Getting away from Harvard.  (Smiling; pause.)  Harvard was fun.  [Okay; pause.]  Only there for two (2) years.  (Smiling.)</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[7:20] Were you lonely and stayed in your room and didn’t go to classes (Sandberg chuckles) and gamed like Bill Gates?
Pause.</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[7:24] I - I have a funny story about that.  [Alright, go ahead.]  But, um, but anyhow, so - so [no I want to hear the funny story, Mark.  (Small airy laugh of disbelief.)]  Well this is a - this is a story too.  (Smiling.)  So - So [alright, okay] so we- (pause) answered (smiles) your original question.  [Alright.]  So, we, um, when we moved out to California just for the summer, and originally, I mean, we weren’t think about starting a company or anything like that.  I remember explicitly thinking (short pause) that there are so many great companies our here and you drive down 101, right [mhm], and you see Yahoo! and all these great companies.  [mhm]  And, um (swallows; pause), I was thinking, you know, it would just be great to spend some time out here for the summer and get to know some of these companies (inhales; pause), and maybe one (1) day I’ll - I’ll build a company as a part of something, but - but this isn’t that company.  [okay]  Um (scoffing laugh), [okay, not this] so, yeah, then, um, then at the end of, uh, (pause) a- at the end of that summer a bunch of us just ended up just staying out in California, and Harvard has this policy where you can take off as much time as you want and then go back whenever, so [short pause; mhm] we took off a term and then we took off another term and (pause) now we’re here.  (Smiles.)</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[8:17] Okay.  What’s your funny story?  (Long pause; Zuckerberg smiles; Audience laughs.)  Is that it?</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[8:21] No that wasn’t the funny story.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[8:22] Okay, so-  What about Harvard and being lonely.  Were you a lonely person there or what?
(Swisher and Audience laughing; Zuckerberg smiling and laughing.)</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[8:29] I’m a shy person.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[8:30] You- you’re somewhat shy.  You’re not quite as shy as Bill Gates.  Did you stay- did you (hesitation) like the high- college experience?  What was (pause; Zuckerberg starts talking) the-</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[8:36] Yeah.  College was good.  Actually it was - it was really funny listening to Bill yesterday talking about he never went to class.  Uh, [uh-huh], it - it reminded me of this story when- it was actually wo-one (1) of the w-one (1) of the applications that (pause) that I think is pretty similar to how people use Facebook to - to share information together, which is- (inhales) they - they have this core curriculum at Harvard, where you have to take certain types of classes [mhm] and they have this Lit and Arts requirement.  And I remember I was taking this class, The Rome of Augustus (pause), [mhm] where you had to (pause), um (pause), i- it was just all - all about art in the time of Augustus and Rome.  [mhm]  And, um (pause; swallows), I didn’t go to class the whole term [okay], and then during reading period (pause) B- Bill was talking about ho- how he studied a lot and made up everything there and - and learned it before the final.  (Inhales.)  And, um (long pause), I was planning on doing that, but, instead (pause), that’s (short pause) when we built Facebook [okay], so -so, I didn’t really (Audience laughs; Zuckerberg smiles) so I didn’t really have anytime then, so - so a few days before this class’s final exam was going to be taking (pause), uh (looks up), I think it was some number of images from - from the class’s artwork and being able to explain the historical significance of them.  So, I just went to the- went to the course website and downloaded all the images (pause) and made a little website where each one (1) of the images had its own page, and you could (pause) put, um (pause), a- and people could go and add comments to the page and [mhm] and explain what was going on.  And - and then I sent a link out to the classlist saying, “Hey I built a study tool.”  (Smiling.)  And, um, (Audience, Sandburg and Swisher laughing hard; whistling) within-  (Stopped because of laughing.)  [[10:03] That is a funny story.]  So, with- within a half an hour it just- all - all the information of all the (Audience and Swisher laughing; Zuckerberg smiling) the pieces of artwork were there, and, um, and (pause) I - I think I- well I passed the course I don’t remember what I got, but I remember the professor told me some time after that the course- that the grades on the final [right] were better than he expected them to be.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[10:20] Wow.  That’s great.  Good for you.  (Zuckerberg laughing.)  It’s like Stone Soup.  So, you-</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[10:24] I - I don’t understand that reference.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[10:26] Alright.  I’ll tell you that later.
Audience, Zuckerberg, and Swisher laughing.</participant>
        <participant name="Sheryl Sandberg">[10:29] I don’t understand it either.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[10:31] You know, I’m telling my kids later, I could make a joke, but I’m not going to but-  Um (pause), so, you (short pause) you did the Harvard thing too, but a little differently.  [Uh-huh.]  Uh, people, Sheryl’s been with Google for a long time, but Google’s all (Sandberg smiling) about Larry and Sergey sitting on an exercise ball pretty much (Sandberg smiles and nods), in terms of public image.  And you have been one (1) of the major executives there for a long time.  Let’s talk a little bit about how you guys ga- got to, and then we’ll talk about why (emphasis) you came to Facebook (Sandberg nodding) too.  Um, you start Harvard- you like the pedigree all over the place.  [smiles; “I graduated.”]  You graduated from Harvard.  [Yeah. Nods.]  You went to Harvard, and then you went to Harvard again?  Or wha- [pause; nodding; back for business school] back for business school.  (Sandberg nodding.)  And you were involved in government w- what was the - what was the [nods; I was in the-] you were in a whole different career path before you got Google.  Was - was- it seems very (pause), you know, very- Harvard business- Harvard, Harvard business school kind of thing, what did - what did you imagine your life was going to be before - before- pre-Google kind of thing.</participant>
        <participant name="Sheryl Sandberg">[11:17] Pre-Google I’d work for the government.  During the Clinton year I worked in the Treasury Department with, uh, Larry Summers.  [mhm]  That’s his Chief of Staff.  [mhm]  And then- [Any funny stories?  No, sorry.]  Lots of funny stories.  None of which I’ll share.  (Okay; smiles.)  That not being the topic for today.  [Okay, okay.]  Uh (some laughter in the Audience), but after that (pause) needed a job, they elect a new president therefore you have to get a new job, and they kind of kick you out of office, it’s in the constitution, and stuff.  [right]  So, needed a job, uh, came out to Silicon Valley, and (pause; hesitation) met people and really wanted to work in technology.  [right]  And met Larry and Sergey.  [And why technology?  I’m curious.]  Because if you’re sitting at the Treasury or anywhere and you’re looking for at a macro-sense about what striving the economy, and it was pretty obvious that it was technology.  [mhm]  And so if you want to be a part of building companies or businesses or organizations technology seemed t- for me at least, to be the obvious place to be.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[11:59] So you had- did you have other job offers somewhere else?</participant>
        <participant name="Sheryl Sandberg">[12:02] I had some others.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[12:03] That were much more traditional?</participant>
        <participant name="Sheryl Sandberg">[12:04] (Nods.)  That were much (nodding) more traditional.  I really wanted to come out to Silicon Valley.  [okay]  And it was a weird time to come to Silicon Valley, in that it was (inhales; pause), the beginning of 2001, huge lay-offs (pause), post-bubble, at least (pause) then.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[12:15] Right, sure.</participant>
        <participant name="Sheryl Sandberg">[12:15] And, you know, I didn’t have the obvious backgrounds, but some people were nice to me and met me and (pause) wound up at Google and-  (Pause.)  You know, loved Google.  Google-</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[12:23] And (pause) talk a little bit about Google your Google experience.  You know, again a lot of people don’t a lot of the executives at Google.  There are several here that you wouldn’t recognize [mhm] necessarily.  What did - what did- w- w-  (Pause.)  How did you look at that experience, being there?
Pause.</participant>
        <participant name="Sheryl Sandberg">[12:35] (Inhales.)  You know, when I (pause) was at the Treasury, the Treasury was a hundred and forty thousand (140,000) people; it was a large (emphasis) organization that worked in very specific ways.  (Inhales.)  So, for me, I wanted to go somewhere small and help build something.  (Nodding.)  Having a sense, that you’ve - you’ve started the right way; you could (pause) build it.  It might be more (pause;), you know, creative (pause) then [mhm; pause] the Treasury.  [right]  Um, and got really lucky.  You know, lucky Larry and Sergey hired me and believed in me, and (pause) built out what was the online sales channel and a bunch of the operations for Google.  (Nodding.)</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[13:01] And what do you think the key to that velocity was, which Tom was just talking about here.  Wh- what was the key into getting that kind of velocity going?  Like finding that one (1) business plan (pause) that’s like (hesitation) owning the heroine business of all time?  Or what-</participant>
        <participant name="Sheryl Sandberg">[13:12] Well, I think it was something similar to what I see in Mark and one (1) of the reasons I made this move.  (Inhales.)  Is an incredible focus (pause) on what you’re trying to do, while you’re trying to do it, not on the people who are using your products.  [mhm]  Someone gave me a great T-shirt at one (1) of these conferences that says, you know, “Make peop- make something that people want.”  [mhm]  You know, really product focused on the user.  At Google, you know, every conversation was about the user, and similarly at Facebook all the conversations come down to the users.  What are they doing?  How are they doing it?  (Inhales.)  Developer ecosystem, advertiser ecosystem, all centers back on (pause) how we are changing lives for the users.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[13:42] Okay.  Let me get back to you before pre-Sheryl Google, I mean, pre-Sheryl Facebook.  So here you come, you get this funding, celebrated, uh, you were a hot thing.  I mean, you have been the hot thing this past year, and we like our hot things since Silicon Valley.  Wi- a- wi- talk about (Zuckerberg smiles) the impact that- you wanted to stay the leader of this company, correct?  (Zuckerberg slightly nods.)  You wanted to always stay the leader.  Let me get something straight.  Did you actually have a card that said-  (Pause; Zuckerberg smiles.)  Did you?  I - I don’t know.  I-  [It was a joke that someone made for me.]  Someone made- he had this card that said, “I’m the CEO, bitch.”  Correct?  And it was- you didn’t mean to had it out.  Did you?</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[14:11] (Inhales.)  No I definitely did not mean to give it to the journal.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[14:13] Okay.  I just wanted to clear that up.  I (Zuckerberg smiling; Zuckerberg, Swisher, and Audience laugh.)  It’s like the Pez Dispensers at E-bay.  It’s one (1) of those ridiculous legends.  (Inhales.)  Uh.  (Zuckerberg smiling; inhales.)</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[14:21] So, um (Pause; Zuckerberg smiling), you - you want- what - what made you want to stay (pause) in charge of this company at - at- when a lot of founders do get moved aside.  They do get- bring in, uh (hesitation), you - you brought in, obviously, Sheryl and different people, but you wanted to stay the (pause) the supreme leader of this company.  The CEO.  What- tell me why you thought- what you think you bring to the- why that’s important.</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[14:39] Yeah.  Sure.  I mean, I think what we’re doing here is (pause) we’re helping people share information and share themselves.  And that’s been this trend that’s been happening for - for a while, but we’ve also built a lot of products at Facebook (pause) that have kind of furthered that in a lot of ways.  Whether it’s just the initial product (inhales) of helping people share different (pause) interests of theirs or, um, different classes that they are taking, starting college, um, the privacy settings, things like (pause) the Photos application, the Wall, um, Newsfeed, like pretty innovative products that help people share more information and get more information.  And recently the development Platform [mhm] that allows (pause) any developer in the world [which we’ll talk about in a little bit] to be able to-  Yeah.  - to be able to, um, to just build even more applications that make it so that people can share information in different ways on the service.  (Pause; inhales.)  We’re nowhere near the end of this trend.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[15:25] Obviously.  But I’m asking, “Why you?”  Why do you - why do you wanna- what’s - what’s been- what do you see that you’re the-  I asked Jerry this.  He didn’t quite answer it, but why are you the leader?  Why did you feel like that you needed to be the-</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[15:35] Well, I think that the CEO basically does two (2) things.  (Pause.)  They (short pause) set the vision for the company (pause), and they recruit a team. (Long pause; [mhm].)  And, you know, so far I think we have this vision, and we’re in the middle of executing on it.  We’re (pause) only four (4) years in, so I think that there is a lot left to go (pause; inhales), and, you know (pause), building a team is the other really important piece of that, and - and spending a lot of time focused on that.  And (pause), you know, getting Sheryl to join was a huge thing for us.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[15:57] Right.  Alright let’s talk about the- before that.  I’m not going to n- n- focus on Beacon we’ve- I’ve written a lot it so-  But what was the - what was a thing you learned in some of the (pause) more error prone things?  What - what have you learned in this first ye-, essentially first (pause) couple years as a CEO.  What’s the-  (Pause.)  Wha- wha- what have you learned about leadership and - and being that; doing that.  Like in taking away from Beacon, and you don’t have to about it in detail, but what did it teach you- what was the thing that you walked away from that with.</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[16:22] About management and leadership specifically or just about [just about what - what you’re doing] what we’re doing?  (Inhales.)  Well (short pause), I think the - the thing that we kind of had to workout (pause) was- there - there are a lot of different ways to get people- (pause) to - to help people share information about themselves, and to share themselves to the people around them.  And the formula that we’ve found that has really worked is (short pause), you give people control (longer pause), and they’ll share (pause) a - a- mu - more information about themselves.  They’ll - they’ll be comfortable. They’ll - they’ll be able to (short pause) c- um, control exactly who they’re sharing information with, and that’s how people are able to open up and communicate better.  [Mhm; pause; inhales.]  So, I mean (pause), I mean, you didn’t want to bring up Beacon, but I will.  [okay]  Um, I mean, I think [go right ahead], uh, Beacon was - was the big mistake for us in - in a lot of ways, but, I mean, one (1) of the things that we really learned from that was (pause) to just reinforce this point to us.  That they’re lots of different ways to go about helping people share information (pause), and the ways that we’re- the ones that we’re- the ones that are successful for us are the oneks where we’re giving people complete control.  So when we fail (long pause) then we end up in situations like that.  And when we succeed we end up creating a lot more transparency among us.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[17:19] (Starts talking over Zuckerberg.)  Was Beacon actually a - a mistake (pause) conceptually?  The idea of it?  Because you’re trying a new advertisment paradigms.  I mean, I don’t necessarily think it was (pause) a mistake conceptually.  It was more executionally in a lot of ways and then how it was-</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[17:30] (Talks over Swisher.)  Well, I mean, it fits into (pause) a lot of thing that we are trying to do, but (pause) I - I think the UI was - was not as good as it could have been.  It really- the things that we needed to have- that we do have to be clear.  Right?  [mhm]  And people need to have control over the information [mhm] that they’re sharing.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[17:42] I’m curious why, for example, in Beacon you didn’t make that- the stuff that people were already sharing like Flickr or YouTube, or make it first not (pause) an ad (emphasis) product.  Make it a product that was (shrugs) useful.</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[17:52] (Inhales.)  Well, it was interesting because, I mean, functionally within the organization (pause), um (longer pause), Beacon is part of the Platform team it’s not even a part of the Ad team.  [mhm]  And we launched it as [right] apart of the ad system [right], um, but - but, I mean, that’s not even how we view it ourselves.  And [right] since the we - we have launched ad- additional products in - in this Feed importing product where you can import from other services [right] like that.  (Nodding.)  Yeah.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[18:11] And not necessarily the- in the ad (no) sense.  [yeah] In that, things that I want (not ads) to mean to share elsewhere on the web.  Let’s talk about wu- a- i- i- where you’re going next and the Platform and, um, monetization, which is my obsession.  I’m not that- I - I do make fun of- about widgets being useless and juvenile, but, and I do want to talk about that, but, um (laughs), I do want to get to that, but let’s first talk about wha- what - what decision-making did you cu- come from Google?  Here you are at the (pause), you know, the powerful company of Google, who is now- which is now the big (pause) dog.  (Pause.)  How- what kind of decision-making went into that?</participant>
        <participant name="Sheryl Sandberg">[18:41] (Smiling; inhales.) You know, I was inspired.  (Pause; [Okay].)  I think, the, uh, web is changing and evolving if the kind of the first phase and, you know, it’s kind of hard to put things it phases, but (pause) if the first phase was about accessing information, which was largely an anonymous process.  I look at- we know you but a lot of people- your website is anonymous.  They’re not interacting with you directly.  They’re reading.  [right]  And then, you know, they can post.  We think increasing or I think increasingly (pause) this is becoming more social.  The web is enabling people to really form communities, and to bring (pause) the ties that are so much a part of their life (pause) into what they are doing online and then back into their life.  And I saw this trend happening and (pause) was excited by it.  Um, and then met Mark and was inspired by him because he [mhm] really does have a sense of vision and purpose about what this company is trying to do and how - how it was going to get there.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[19:25] (Talks over Sandberg) Had you - had you reached a boredom at Google?  What was the- you were on maternity leave I know, and you (pause; Sandberg nodding) and you were looking around.  You were-</participant>
        <participant name="Sheryl Sandberg">[19:32] (Smiling.)  I had not quite started.  I was on maternity leave, had my second child, went back (pause), um (pause), and then (long pause) was kind of approached about (pause) some other things that weren’t at Google and were at Facebook.  (Inhales.)  And I had been there about six and a half (6 ½) years and looking for something new.  (Inhales; pause.)  And then (long pause; nodding) very interested in what this company was trying to do, and what I saw as the evolution of practices on the web.  (Inhales.)  And also excited by the opportunity to go again to something that was small.  I mean, the opportunity to go to Google I joined when it was about (pause) two hundred and sixty (260) people and help build something.  (Pause.)  To have those opportunities are hard to find [mhm], and this is one (1) of those opportunities.  (Inhales.)  And, so to be able to go to a company that I really (emphasis) believe in the mission and vision of what it’s trying to do (pause), and then help it scale (pause), you know, make slightly fewer mistakes than I made last time, is-  Might just be opportunity of a lifetime.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[20:16] (Talks over Sandberg; smiling.)  What’s your biggest- what was your- what was your biggest mistake?</participant>
        <participant name="Sheryl Sandberg">[20:17] Oh, there are so many.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[20:18] Okay.  (Sandberg laughs.)  Um, we can get into that in a second.  Let’s talk about, um, the opening of the Platform.  (Pause.)  About what you’re doing.  You’re undergoing right now a - a Platform change right now of - of (longer pause) basically prettying up the service and cleaning it up and doing- changing the way it looks for people everything.  We’ll get to that in a second.  But you were the first to open up the Platform to these third parties, which is- I think most people feel is a smart move.  I mean, I do.  I think it was really a (inhales) great idea and people are copying it now.  Yahoo! talk about it in a very broad way today, (inhales) but what, um, wi- i- talk about that experience opening up and the - and the pitfalls and the things maybe you (pause) haven’t liked so much and the things that you think have be stronger?
(Zuckerberg) [20:55] Sure.  (Long pause.)  So (longer pause), I me- mean, the - the original reason why we wanted to open up is that we saw there were all of these different social application that - that we could build (pause; [mhm]) to help people share information in different way, but we realized that we were never going to be abl- to be able to build all of them.  And we also realize that we weren’t (pause) even going to be able to identify all of the interesting ones that - that could be built.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[21:15] (Starts at the very end of Zuckerberg talking.)  So we’re back to the study guide then.  Okay.  Go ahead.</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[21:17] Yeah, sure.  So (pause) so, I mean (pause), building the - the Development Platform to make it so that any outside developer could make build all the same types of applications that we could inside of Facebook would kind of just allow anyone across the world to help us explore the space of possible applications.  ([Mhm]; inhales.)  Um, I - I think in the first year we’ve- it’s been pretty good. It grew a lot.  [mhm]  Faster than we even thought it would.  I mean, it’s more than three hundred thousand (300,000) developers now, and, um (pause), and a lot of different applications.  And (pause), you know, I mean, there - there are really interesting and good ones too in verticals that (inhales; pause) that we hadn’t really anticipated or that we specifically not gone after ourselves.  So, for example, music.  We purposely didn’t build a music application ‘cause we didn’t want to get involve in that, but within four (4) days of releasing Platform (pause), um, this company, iLike, had built a music application that [right] had a million users.  [One (1) of the more successful-]  Right, so - so that’s pretty interesting.  I mean, a- another category that I think is pretty interesting is- (pause) we hadn’t done anything with games, ([games]; pause) on the site.  And, I mean, that’s a big way that people interact socially.  And there have been applications like Scrabulous that (swallows; pause) I think, um, Walt mentioned earlier ([games]; pause), and, um, it was just built by a couple of guys in India and-</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[22:25] A little bit of issues around that.  With copyright (Zuckerberg laughs), but - but, um, okay.  Ga-  There’s a lot of gaming.  [It’ll get worked out.]  They’ll get worked out.  I’m sure they will.  (Zuckerberg smiling;And find them-)  But you’ll shoplift and then work it out.  (Sandberg and Audience laughs.)  But good- um, gu-  But - but the idea of (quick pause) of - of - of these - these things, are you talking about two (2) areas (slight nodding) that I actually think are great.  The gaming.  I just wrote about social gaming network.  Mark, uh, Mark Pincus’s group at Zynga, um (pause), very important.  I do like the music applications.  How- do they have (emphasis) to become useful because again I - I - I - I don’t- I am making a funny joke and a snarky joke but a lot of them seem juvenile, hit-based (pause), silly, and in need (emphasis) of- they’re not Word, they’re not (pause) Excel, they’re not- and nothing has to be as dull as that, but they - they have to have some sort of (Sandberg does a short laugh), um (pause), you know, resonance in your life, usefulness.  C-  What - what has (emphasis) to happen there?  Or do you think it’s just going to be all these entertainment-  (Pause.)  And people can argue- Keith here from Slide argues with me all the time about this, that I’m no fun, and that’s entirely true.  But (pause) wha - what has to (pause) happen in that area to become (pause) daily usage, and you get the uptake from people using every- every person using it everyday?</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[23:28] Mhm.  (Pause.)  Well, I mean, I think that there - there are two (2) things that I’d say to that.  The first is that (pause) there probably are a bunch of applications that (pause) are useful in a more traditional sense.  I mean, there this Causes application that allows people to [it’s very nice] to raise money for, you know, different fill and non-profit causes and raise awareness, and, I mean, that’s a serious application.  Right?  [mhm]  It’s doing serious good.  (Inhales; pause.)  And then there’s this other trend on the internet, which is to just that utility and usefulness doesn’t necessarily have to be this big thing anymore it can take place in - in a lot of little interactions.  [mhm]   Right, so a - a lot of what’s happening on - on Facebook and trends on the web are, people post a little bit on content, but they do it more frequently.  Right, and we’re seeing that with things like status updates they’re just really short pieces of content.  Um, even (pause) people uploading photos (short pause) that people more likely now (emphasis; short pause; inhales through nose) to upload things like a mobile photo.  One (1) mobile photo.  [mhm]  Right then they - they were before.  This - this trend is toward much smaller more frequent updates.  Right?  [right]  And that’s how people are sharing themselves online.  [right]  So, I mean, so a lot of these other things that (pause) that you - you might look at and - and traditionally say don’t look like Microsoft Word or Excel [right] can still be really useful.  [mhm]  I don’t know do (turns head to look at Sandberg) you have (pause) any. . . .</participant>
        <participant name="Sheryl Sandberg">[24:33] Yeah, you know, my roommate in college was an Elvis fan, and that wasn’t very popular.  And she had a button, which she wore sometimes which said, “A hundred million Elvis fans can’t be wrong.”  [right]  And joking aside, you know, can twenty (20) mil-  [I - I’m a huge Elvis fan.]  Perfect.  [I’ve been to Tupelo.  So don’t-]  But can twenty (20) million people who are spending time poking each other, Max is here, thank you for that application it’s very popular.  (Inhales.)  But (pause) can that be wrong or is that not have value?  And (pause) we - we understand that we want our developers to continue to work and integrate more into user’s lives (inhales) but we also think there’s real value being created in the things that seem whimsical and fun.  (Inhales; Swisher starts talking.)  And-</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[25:05] Okay.  I agree.  They have value.  Stupid pet trick have value, too.  But, I mean, where is the - the advertising para- how- do you begin- is that how you become a serious advertising biz-   How do you translate [yeah], um, and I know a lot of shows make a lot of money.  They’re silly and stupid, and (pause), you know, half of the shows on television today are (pause) getting dumber.  (Inhales.)  Um, w- how do you - how do you translate it into a new advertising paradigm?  ‘Cause that’s what you were talking about Mark.  You - you made this grand statement about changes in advertising.  How do you see you explaining that to people and getting that to port over.  (Short pause.)  Besides peop- lots of people using them.  They’ve got to feel like it’s a useful - useful spend for a- Budweiser practically [yeah; nodding] gambled [no, of course] those people.</participant>
        <participant name="Sheryl Sandberg">[25:45] (Inhales.)  I mean, wo- one (1) thing that’s- what’s really worked online and obviously something we’re all really familiar with is, “What is demand fulfillment.”  [mhm]  The majority of online spend where people are most satisfied, marketers, advertisers is demand fulfillment.  Someone knows what they are looking for they can get it.  We knew we wanted a princess phone once we heard about it this morning.  [okay]  We did a search, we found it, it was a target-  [Where’d you search?]  Uh, I didn’t do it.  We had someone do it.  (Zuckerberg laughs.)  But probably Google.  ([Alright]; Zuckerberg laughing.)  I hope Google.  (Smiles and laughs; inhales.)  I still remain loyal.  But (pause), you know, we knew what we were doing.  It was demand fulfillment.  But a larger part of what is advertising spending all over the world is in demand generation, traditional brand spending.  ([Right]; inhales.)  And the question there is, “How do you capture people’s attention and engage and involve?”  Even when they don’t know what they are looking for.  (Inhales.)  And one (1) of the reasons I came to Facebook (pause) was because I think Facebook has a really unique opportunity to fulfill that (emphasis) vision and fulfill that mission.  (Inhales.)  So our users tell us a lot about themselves [mhm], and they’re telling us what they like, what they don’t like, what they do.  And that gives us an opportunity to provide- to work with advertisers to provide them information that’s actually useful.  (Inhales.)  And, you know, everyone talks about targeting, and everyone (quick pause) tries [privacy] to work on it.  We’re working on it too, and privacy.  And, of course, we mean it in a (pause), you know totally anonymous way, but do we think we can use what we know, work with users to pro- use advertisers to provide things that are great for you users.  Absolutely.  (Inhales.)  But I think (pause) we have a s-econd (pause) level, which we can do.  Which is, we think we can offer real engagement.  (Pause.)  So, the dream (emphasis) of advertisers is to (pause) create demand for something, and then let people engage with the products.  So, I’ll share one (1) example.  (Pause.)  Uh, end of April Ben &amp; Jerry’s does their free cone day [mhm].  I guess they do it once a year, or so.  (Inhales.)  And they did an advertising campaign with us.  Where we have these free gif- these sponsored gifts, and they sponsored the gift.  And they gave out two hundred and fifty thousand (250,000) cones, which means users without paying a dollar could give cones to each other.  ([Mhm]; inhales.)  So within a couple of hours two hundred and fifty thousand (250,000) cones were given out.  So Ben &amp; Jerry’s bought another two hundred and fifty thousand (250,000) cones.  So, within eleven (11) hours five hundred thousand (500,000) people had sent these free cones.  (Inhales; pause.)  There was also a link to the Ben &amp; Jerry’s store locator where it told everyone, “Today is Ben &amp; Jerry’s free cone day.  (Short pause.)  You can come.”  And people used our Events page to say, “Oh I’m doing this,” and invite each other.  (Inhales.)  By the time this was done within twenty-four (24) hours, we think there was something like fifty-three (53) million impressions (pause) on Ben &amp; Jerry’s.  [mhm]  Users telling Ben &amp; Jerry’s on their page what kind of flavors they like.  People telling each other they were going to cone day.  (Inhales; facial expression; pause.)  I’m not going to sit here and tell you all the advertising on Facebook has that property because (pause; [no]) we both know they don’t.  [For me, for some reason, it’s viagra.]  You’ll skewer me.  Yeah, we know that.  We know that.  But that is the vision. [mhm]  And that’s a pretty Facebook unique opportunity.  For a brander to create awareness and strive to specific user engagement.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[28:18] So, Mark, do you feel you have to educated advertisers in that way?  In terms of new paradigms, or are you doing something very old, like (pause), “Here’s I’m building-”  (Inhales.)  I think you’re a media company more.  You often call yourself a technology company, but you’re med- you’re - you’re [[14:12] we’re definitely a technology company] your defin-  (Zuckerberg smiles and he, the Audience, and Sandberg laugh.)  Okay, you’re definitely a technology.  Why are you not a media company?
Pause.</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[28:35] (Inhales.)  Well, I - I mean, i- it depend on how you’re defining a media company.  I mean, I think we’r-</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[28:38] You’re building an audience, and selling that audience.</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[28:41] Sure, I mean-</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[28:41] You’re keeping them entertained (Zuckerberg smiling) in some fashion, or keeping them (pause) occupied and (long pause) happy.</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[28:45] I think we’re primarily building technology.  (Laughing and smiling.)</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[28:48] Okay.  Explain that.  Explain that.</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[28:49] No, I mean, I think we’re building a lot of products in different ways that people can share information.  [mhm]  Right, I mean, the focus that’s really important with these internet companies (pause) that the focus continues to be on the product and - and on (pause; [right]) engineering and - and the technology behind it.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[29:01] So it’s the tool- the technology tools are your media.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[29:05] That makes you a technology company?  And would you compare yourself in a technology company to Google?  Are you a (pause) Google-like technology company or-</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[29:12] Um, I mean, I - I don’t know-</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[29:15] Well what-  [Smiling.  - what you mean.]  How - how would you define.  I’m interested in how you would define what technology companies is today, going forward.</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[29:19] I think it’s one (1) that’s mostly (Swisher nods) focused on - on building technology and building (pause) building things.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[29:24] Building (pause) technology pro- online [yeah] technology products.  Alright, let’s talk about u - u- but in terms of changing the face of advertising is it- are you going to do something very (slight emphasis) different (pause) or - or finding- you’re going to have to educate advertisers in a lot of ways.  Do you feel like it’s using something different or the same kind of thing (Zuckerberg inhales to start talking; pause) in just a new formats?</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[29:41] Well, I mean, it’s a lot of the broader trend that - that we’ve been talking about today (quick pause) in terms of the product.  Are - are- the - the broader promise that Sheryl was speaking to, but I  - I also think there is this process of bringing people along for that and - and moving from where we are today towards that.  So, I mean (turns to face Sheryl), Sheryl can probably speak more to that.</participant>
        <participant name="Sheryl Sandberg">[29:56] Yeah, I think (pause) this is what people have always wanted.  It is (short pause; shaking her head)- goes back way before the internet.  You know, what do you do if you’re in marketing?  You create awareness of a product; then you try to get users engaged; then you try to move them on down the funnel to trial, to experimentation, to use, to repurchase.  (Runs out of breath at the end of sentence; inhales.)  Right?  What we’re doing is-  (Pause.)  We are a technology company bringing technology to that.  So (pause), so very quickly going back to the Ben &amp; Jerry’s example or (pause), you know, the Indiana Jones example.  We did a free gift for that (inhales; pause) last week (pause) for the opening.  (Pause.)  We brought people to awareness [sure] Indiana Jones opening, send the free fedora, go to the movie.  [okay]  And so it’s technology speeds everything up.  That’s what we’ve seen.  (Inhales.)  We think technology can speed up (pause) the interaction between advertisers and users (short pause) in ways that’s really good (emphasis) for users.  (Pause; [okay].)  And that’s [let-] where we’re really focused.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[30:37] Let me talk about two (2) more problems.  Change.  Change of what you are doing.  You’re changing the Platform.  Can you very briefly tell us what - what that means right now?  What is - what is the Platform gonna look like, and how- uh, people are going to complain no matter what we changed the comics, Don Graham can tell you, in The Washington Post, and we had (Sandberg laughs) protests for years.  You know (Sandberg coughs), we - we moved Nancy, which is never funny, and it was like (pause), I don’t know, the “Crisis of (pause) 1983.”  (Inhales.)  So what, uw - uw- what do you - what do you going to do that’s gonna sort of change it, and how do you feel people are going to react to what you’re doing there?</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[31:06] (Inhales.)  Well, I mean, the - the main thing that we’re doing is (pause), if - if you look at the original (short pause) version of Platform that we had.  It was very focused on developers building these boxes that could go in people’s profiles [right], and then users going in and installing [the boxes] di-fferent boxes in their profiles.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[31:20] And moving boxes around.</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[31:21] Yeah, and - and, I mean (short pause), one (1) of the things that happened was that the - the Platform just grew so quickly and there are so many applications that people installed a ton of these.  (Pause.)  Right, and (pause), um (long pause), the, uh (pause)-  We found that a lot of the focus for developers was just on getting people to install these (short pause) these different boxes as opposed to (pause) actually creating a long-term engagement (inhales; short pause), and (pause) we want to make sure that - that the application (short pause) developers are in-sensitized towards building (inhales) applications that are actually (inhales), um, trustworthy to users.  They go back a lot (emphasis) and (pause) engaging to users so we’re - we’re moving the system away from this box based system to more of a system where when activities happening it can go people’s pages, and - and [right] people approve of that.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[32:01] So you’re going to have this sort of tab kind of - tab kind of thing.  (Nodding.)</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[32:03] Yeah, so the net effect of- I think of the - the new iteration of Platform is going to be that (inhales; pause) applications that are more engaging and that users trust more are going to be the ones that spread through the system more.  They’re going to get more distribution.  They’re going to be in people’s pages more.  (Inhales.)  And (pause) I- it’s also just going to help people share information (pause) a - a lu- (pause) a lot more easily, through (pause) through Feeds as opposed to through these boxes.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[32:23] Okay.  Let me get another chance change within your company.  I’ve watched a lot of companies, Netscape, AOL, all of them change (emphasis; slows down).  How is the entrance of Sheryl, you’ve just hired Elliot Schrage from Google, I’m not sure who you’re hiring from Google next (inhales), but, um, wha- what, uh, wa - wa- how is that- how is that- is that hard on the earlier people?  I mean, even though you are a very young company can be very vexing to early people as you shift (emphasis).  What’s gonna be different now.  You’re bringing much more professional co- un - un- [yeah] managers.</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[32:51] (Pause; thinking facial expression.)  I mean, I think its just- its scaled really quickly.  (Long pause.)  Um (long pause), I - I don’t know.  (Turns to look at Sandberg.)  What’s the change that you’ve seen since you’ve been here?</participant>
        <participant name="Sheryl Sandberg">[32:59] It’s hard for me to compare the (short pause; [yeah].) nine (9) weeks I’ve been there before.  But I think the (emphasis) company (pause) is (emphasis) scaling really quickly, and people want (pause), you know (pause), to make their jobs great and to build great products.  And (pause) finding ways to bring, you know, some of the things that we’re working on is changing and improving our recruiting process.  [mhm]  That’s gone over very well.  (Pause; [mhm].)  We’ve tightened it up; we’ve shortened it.  You know, we’re trying to make sure we’re hiring the best people doing thorough reference checks, et cetera, and (shaking her head and one (1) shoulder shrug; pause) I think that’s helping people get their jobs done faster.  And that’s obviously what we’re trying to do.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[33:27] More of the “trains run on time” kind of stuff.</participant>
        <participant name="Sheryl Sandberg">[33:29] Yeah.  (Side head bob.)  And - and execute-</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[33:30] (Cuts Sandberg off.)  Which you’re well known you.  I’ll have to say.</participant>
        <participant name="Sheryl Sandberg">[33:31] And ex-  Well, you know.  [yeah]  I’m glad to be well known for that because I think that’s important.  You can have all the vision in the world, but as we saw from so (emphasis) many people sitting on this stage (pause), the people that have, you know (pause), earned (emphasis) their right to be on stage by building amazing (emphasis) companies.  It’s about having a vision, and then about execution.  (Inhales.)  And that’s really what we want to do is (one (1) shoulder shrug) both.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[33:48] Let’s talk about that vision and execution.  (Pause.)  A- are you (pause) are you interested in selling to Microsoft?  Your company?  For fifteen (15) billion dollars ($)?</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[33:54] No.  I think you know that by now.  (Smiling.)
Sandberg laughs.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[33:56] I know that.  I know that.  You- what are you interested in (pause) interested in?  IPO?  Exactly (strong emphasis) what are you interested in, or do you-</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[34:01] (Inhales.)  No, I mean, I think-</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[34:01] (Cuts Zuckerberg off.)  If you- if they walked up to you and said, “Fifteen (15) billion dollars ($), Mark Zuckerberg.”  And you have (long pause; nodding) had a set of them.  I’ve gotta say.  You’ve really have with- have withstood a lot of, uh-  

(Swisher, Audience, and Zuckerberg laughing; Zuckerberg smiling.)  You- I mean, you’ve withstood a lot.  I - I would have been gone way, way back.  (Sandberg and Audience laughing; Zuckerberg smiles.)  And in France right now.  (Sandberg laughing.)  So, um, what i- u-  They- “Fifteen (15) billion dollars ($), Mark Zuckerberg.”  Steve- he - he 

(Zuckerberg wets his lips) says, (impersonating low, gravelly voice) “We’re coming!  We’re coming!  We’re coming!  Fifteen (15) billion!”
Audience laughs.</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[34:27] (Smiling.)  Well - well, I mean, I think the - the goal of the company is to just, uh - uh, execute on some of things that we talked about before.  I mean, just helping (pause) people (pause) become more open and share more information.  

(Inhales; pause.)  Um (long pause), that- that’s the goal.  (Pause.)  Right, so-</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[34:39] Right, but I’m coming, coming, coming with fifteen (15) billion, what?</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[34:41] (Smiling.)  So - so how does that help us?  Right?</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[34:43] Does it?</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[34:43] So (pause) so, I mean, I - I-  The goal- the end goal for us isn’t to sell the company or to IPO.  I mean, the way that we evaluate things like that (pause) are just, “How are they going to help things along the way?”  Right?  And what we are building is (pause) actually what we care about.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[34:56] Can they do- can they sell that company without your say-so?</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[34:59] I don’t think so.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[35:01] Yeah.  (Zuckerberg smiles; Swisher laughs a little.)  Okay.  Then lastly what do you wake-  (Audience and Sandberg laughing; Zuckerberg smiles.)  You don’t think so?  You’d better find out.  (Zuckerberg nods.)  I’ll find out for you from all my sources there.  Um. [Go for it.  Smiling.]  Okay.  Um, I believe so.  I think they can’t do a thing without you.  Um (pause), many people could learn from you I think.   Um, in that regard.  Um, so in terms of, um, the Microsoft, Yahoo! situation (Zuckerberg swallows) how do you look at that?  I mean do you - you- are you going to be a part of that?  A part-  Do you see you- your own one (short pause) one point six (1.6) percent (%)?  And we saw the little movie.  It was cute.  
(Zuckerberg, small smile)  Do they call you a lot?  Do they-  (Sandberg laughs; Zuckerberg smiles.)  What is their role in your-</participant>
        <participant name="Sheryl Sandberg">[35:33] No, it was a joke.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[35:33] No, I got that.</participant>
        <participant name="Sheryl Sandberg">[35:34] Calling card.  Yeah.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[35:34] No, I don’t think they call you at all.  But, um-</participant>
        <participant name="Sheryl Sandberg">[35:36] Well, they call sometimes.  (Zuckerberg turns to look at her.)</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[35:37] Okay.  What is the - what is the (Zuckerberg turns to look at her) relationship there?  With a giant (emphasis; pause) company like Microsoft.</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[35:42] Well. . . .  (Turns to look at Sandberg.)</participant>
        <participant name="Sheryl Sandberg">[35:43] (One (1) shoulder shrug when Zuckerberg turns.)  I guess I took the last trip up there.  It’s - it’s good.  I mean, I think they are very-</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[35:46] You’re just went up there right?</participant>
        <participant name="Sheryl Sandberg">[35:48] (Nods; smiling.)  I did just go up there.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[35:48] I know that was unusual for you.  Correct?</participant>
        <participant name="Sheryl Sandberg">[35:49] (Smiling.)  Well, coming from Google you don’t spend a lot of time at Microsoft.  So it was my-  (Sandberg smiling and laughing with Audience.)  It was my first trip.  [okay]  I was with someone from Facebook, and (pause) he said to me, “Well we go here.”  And I’m like, “Which way is that?”  And he says, “Well, you’ve never been here?”  And I’m like, “No, no I just spent six (6) years at Google.  (Pausing after every word.  [Right].)  We don’t (pause) travel to Microsoft all that often.”  (Inhales.)  Um (short pause), but (pause) it’s a good partnership.  I mean, I really believe, and I think (short pause), that Google experiences teaches you as well, that you (shaking her head) can’t go it alone.  No company can go it alone.  And (one (1) shoulder shrug) we’re a small company.  I mean, we’re five hundred and fifty people (550), four (4) years old, and not very big.  (Inhales.)  Um, and partnerships really matter.  (Pause.)  And the Microsoft partnership has been important and will continue to be important as we scale.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[36:24] And your relationship with Google?  (Looking back and forth between Sandberg and Zuckerberg; song pause.)  It’s been a little fraught.
Long pause.</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[36:29] Um (pause), I mean, Google’s a great company.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[36:30] (Cuts Zuckerberg off.)  I know you want to sit down and talk with them Mark, but do you really want to sit down and talk with them?</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[36:34] (Smiling.)  Oh, we talk all the time.</participant>
        <participant name="Sheryl Sandberg">[36:35] Well, yeah.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[36:35] I know that.  Uh (exaggerated), please if I hear that one (1) more time from an internet person-</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[36:37] You know, the last time that we talk to (pause) to Larry and Eric at the same time, they came over to my apartment, and. . . .</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[36:42] Okay.  Dinner?  What?  (Sounds frustrated.)  What were you doing?</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[36:44] (Talks over Swisher.)  Well, I don’t have the proper things in my apartment to make dinner.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[36:46] Okay.  (Slight laugh.)
Audience laughs.</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[36:47] (Smiling.)  Um, actually-  (Pause while Audience laughing.)</participant>
        <participant name="Sheryl Sandberg">[36:49] In fact (pause) Eric-</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[36:50] (Cuts Sandberg off.)  I - I have- I - I had- at the time I had a mattress on the floor, and I - I had this little table in the corner [yeah] with two (2) seats.  So - so Larry came over and we were sitting.  And Eric came in, and he had to sit on the floor.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[36:59] Uh-huh.
Audience and Sandberg laughing.</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[37:00] We - we sat on the floor and joined him.
[37:00] I remember that.  At Google.  Eric talked about that.  He went to Mark Zuckerberg’s apartment and had to sit on the floor.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[37:03] I . . . Eric Schmidt.  (Inhales; talks over Sandberg.)  So, um, wha- what did you- what did talk to him about?  What did you - did you envision your relationship with Google?  With the opensocial, with the comp- whatever it is.  What- I don’t even understand, frankly.  (Pause; Zuckerberg smiles.)  So what- how do you (pause) look at there?  You’re - you’re relationship with Google?</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[37:17] (Inhales; slight shaking of his head.)  I mean, they do a lot of interesting things.  I - I - I (pause) think it would be good to work with them on (pause) on something.  I mean, it’s- we - we haven’t worked with them tha- on that much yet.  But it would be good to.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[37:25] Mhm.  What do you think?  (Pause.)  What would be (pause) Search, please for the love of God, (Sandberg laughing; Zuckerberg smiles) invite Facebook.  But - but what do you imagine?  (Pause.)  How do you imagine that (emphasis) type of relationship going?</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[37:33] (Inhales.)  Well, the thing is Google is - is such a big company [mhm] and (pause) it’s doing so many different things (inhales; pause) that, I mean, there - there the pieces that are outside of - of what Facebook is doing, like Search.  (Pause; inhales.)  But, I mean, there - there are also, u-uh, work social stuff a [mhm] a little bit.  Right, I mean, that’s - that’s like somewhat of a focus for them.  So, I mean, it wouldn’t be good to - to talk to them about some of that kind of stuff.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[37:52] (Talks over Zuckerberg.)  What is your viewpoint of opensocial (pause), and how do you (pause) expect to deal with opensocial?</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[37:56] (Inhales.)  Well (small one (1) shoulder shrug), I mean, I think (pause; swallows), uh (thinking facial expression), for - for opensocial (pause) we, um (pause)-  I don’t know.  We’ll have to see how that evolves.  It’s still - it’s still kind of getting started (inhales), um, our Platform is - is mostly focused, at this point, on just helping people build different applications so that users can share information in different ways.  [okay]  Right, and - and-  (Stops.)</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[38:16] And what- let me ask you what motivates you?  I know you have the no apartment with the thing.  What do you- what do you imagine yourself in five (5) years?  (Pause.)  Right now?</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[38:23] (Smiles.)  In terms of. . . .</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[38:24] On your thirtieth birthday (pause), here you are-  (That’s six (6) years.)  Six (6) years.  (Zuckerberg and Audience laugh.)  Okay.  (Don’t age him.)  Okay, thank you math (you’re welcome; pause) queen.  (Sandberg laughs.)</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[38:33] I don’t know.  I just hope-</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[38:33] (Cuts Zuckerberg off.)  With a princess phone like me?  I don’t know.  [I-]  What?</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[38:36] Well, that would be great.  [okay]  I mean, I just don’t know, I just hope that we’re-  (Audience and Zuckerberg laughing.)</participant>
        <participant name="Sheryl Sandberg">[38:39] You can give it back to me.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[38:40] No I’m totally not giving it back to you.  It’s under twenty-five (125) dollars ($) I’m sure.  Go ahead.  (Pause.)  Wher - where do you imagine yourself in five (5) years?  And then we are going to open it up for questions.</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[38:48] (Swallows.)  I - I (short pause) I don’t know.  I just feel that we’re closer to achieving our goals as a - as a company.  In terms of helping people (short pause) make - make themselves more open [and-] and share more information.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[38:56] (Talks over Zuckerberg.)  And do you imagine having another company?</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[38:58] Um (shakes his head), I - I don’t know.  Probably not.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[39:01] Probably not.
Video audio repeats from Zuckerberg saying “. . . people (short pause) make - make themselves more open. . .)</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[39:10] (All three turn out to the audience; Sandberg smiling; Swisher pointing and waving her arm around the audience.) Okay.  Questions (pause) from the audience.  There’s gotta be good questions for Mark and (pause) Sheryl.
Long pause.</participant>
        <participant name="Barry Sonnenfeld">[39:16] Hi.
Sheryl looks toward the speaker, smiling.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[39:18] Oh good.  (Audience laughs; Zuckerberg and Sandberg smiling.)  You.</participant>
        <participant name="Barry Sonnenfeld">[39:20] Uh, yeah.  Un Barry Sonnenfeld, uh, Esquire columnist and (straches head; pause) film director.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[39:24] And all-around Gadsadline.</participant>
        <participant name="Barry Sonnenfeld">[39:26] Uh, yeah.  Um (clears his throat; pause), growing up, uh (long pause), I- was a- you know, I was taught about the right to privacy it was- it’s a big government thing.  You know, anti-government and all that.  And (swallows; pause) I just wonder (pause) if your site (pause)-  My fifteen (15) year old daughter is on your site all the time (pause), and has no (emphasis) sense of (pause) privacy, the nature of privacy, and in fact goes out of her way to publish everything about herself.  (Sandberg laughs a little.)  So I wonder (inhales) so a certain extent (pause) down the road (short pause) do you feel that we’re creating a generation (swallows), my daughter’s generation, and the generation after that where (inhales) there'll be no sense of (pause) fear of (pause) government, fear of, uh, invasion of privacy?  I know you have certain abilities (pause) to (pause) prevent people from getting on anything.  In a fundamental (pause) way, do you feel that we’re creating a sad, dreary future for our (pause) children?
(Audience laughs; video goes to Zuckerberg smiling and laughing.)</participant>
        <participant name="Sheryl Sandberg">[40:24] That’s even true?</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[40:24] And - and let me just, uh-  There’s also a question from the internet.  Hannah from Boston asks Mark Zuckerberg, “What measures is Facebook taking to curb the bullying (emphasis) that leads to violence on your site?”</participant>
        <participant name="Sheryl Sandberg">[40:34] That is very-</participant>
        <participant name="Barry Sonnenfeld">[40:34] That’s  a- that’s a different question.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[40:36] – Sad and dreary violence.  What?  (Pause.)  What are you doing about it?</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[40:38] So, I mean, I actually think it’s the opposite of that.  I mean, there are different ways to get to (pause) to a world where people are sharing more information about themselves, and - and, I mean, one (1) is (short pause) is (pause) through (pause) having (pause) people (pause) basically get hed- force on them.  Right?  Which is the - the government thing that you are probably talking about.  (Inhales.)  But, I mean, the - the world that we’re trying to build towards is one (1) where people have control and are sharing (short pause) this information because they feel comfortable and because (inhales) they’re connected to all these people around them and are able to effectively share the information that they want.  And - and one (1) of the things that (inhales; pause) that makes it so that people can (pause) can share a lot of information (inhales) is that the site is setup so that people aren’t sharing all of their information (inhales) with all the more that seventy (70) million people on the site.  (Pause.)  Right, so, I mean, the people on average have (pause), you know, a network or two (2) and are sharing information with maybe a few thousand (1,000) people.  I mean, you know, a lot of people put on their cell phone number, and the reason for that is because they can say I only want to share this with my friends, and I don’t want to share (emphasis) this with everyone on the site.  (Inhales; pause.)  And, um (swallows), in terms of using the - the privacy settings and things like that (sharp inhale) even though it might seem like (pause) like your daughter isn’t paying that much attention to privacy (inhales; pause) a huge amount of our users are tweaking their privacy settings in different ways.  So it’s actually really (pause) fundamentally part of the site.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[41:48] And you feel so that you caught the violence of bullying?  You’ve heard stories of that.  (Sandberg nods.)  On my- every - every site has- MySpace has had issues.  (Zuckerberg turns toward Sandberg.)  Do you feel you have a (short pause) a - a - a role as a (pause) sheriff (Swisher sets down card) or a Town Hall  I - I don’t know what, a mayor?</participant>
        <participant name="Sheryl Sandberg">[42:00] (Inhales.)  I mean, we certainly have role in making sure our site is secure, and people are sharing information appropriately, and we are (pause) controlling that information with (emphasis) them appropriately, giving (emphasis) them full control of what they want to share.  (Inhales; pause.)  You know, obviously the interactions between everyone (pause) from fifteen (15) year old teenagers to others (short pause) run the full gambit.  (Pause).  From saying, “Hello” to things that are considered bullying.  (Inhales.)  Uh (one (1) shoulder shurg), we think we’ve become useful for communities to monitor - monitor that (pause) themselves (emphasis).  [mhm]  That these things have always gone on.  Facebook actually brings them to light (inhales; pause) more rapidly, and we’ve seen a lot of (pause) distinct communities, schools taking action around that to enforce their own policies.  [Talks behind Sandberg.  Right.]  Which we can enable.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[42:36] (Points out into the audience.)  Over here.</participant>
        <participant name="Allison Sheridan">[42:36] Allison Sheridan from Raytheon.  I’ve, uh, read an article recently that said one (1) of the fastest growing groups in, uh, Facebook is- I think it was thirty-five (35) to fifty (50) year old women (Sandberg laughs) and, uh, even though I’m more than double your age.  (Inhales; small smile.)  Um, are you guys-  I’m - I’m in Facebook, and I love it in there, and I’m having a lot of fun with my sad, dreary children that are in there.  Um (quick pause; Audience laughs), my [like me-]  (Audience and Sheridan laughing.)</participant>
        <participant name="Sheryl Sandberg">[42:56] Hey, that’s my age group.</participant>
        <participant name="Allison Sheridan">[42:57] (Smiling.)  There you go.  So, my question is are you guys doing anything to - to try to build things that would draw my friends in because my generation, my friends (shrugs) aren’t in it.  But - but I’d love if my - my direct friends were.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[43:06] So (pause), beyond Pick Your Zit (pause; Sandberg laughs), for example, the lovely widget that is always my favorite to point to.  What do you - what do you have for her?  (Pause.)  Mark?
Camera goes to Sheridan; Sheridan smiling.</participant>
        <participant name="Zuckerberg">[43:14] Well, I mean, a lot of the theory is that (pause) what we are doing (pause) is pretty applicable to people a-ll over the world and - and of any age.  Right?  I mean, everyone has friends, everyone has (pause) acquaintances, business connections, people that they are connected with, and they need to communicate with these people and (inhales) it’s good to just be able to have a sense of who these people are.  (Sheridan says something, not miked.)  So, I mean there are going to be specific applications that are going to be built for people in different demographics.  And - and in different countries across the world.  (Inhales.)  And a lot of that is happening on top of Platform.  So, I mean, one (1) of the really interesting things is, um (wets his lips; pause), you know, I just travelled to a- around the world for a bit, and I stopped in - in E- Istanbul.  And I sat a a cafe, and I was watching (pause) a - a bunch of people use Facebook, a lot (confused facial expression) of people in Turkey use Facebook.  And, um (pause), there are lot of local (pause) applications that people have built there (pause) that (pause) are - are just things that - that make a lot of sense for Turkish users, and I didn’t understand them (smiles) because I don’t know the language.  (Inhales.)  But - but, I mean (pause), uh- le- that’s a lot of the goodness of - of what we are trying to get at with Platform.  (Pause.)  Right, it people - people can build a lot of applications in these different places for different types of users even if we haven’t gotten to that yet.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[44:16] Did you reveal yourself to them.  I’m just curious.
Sandberg smiling.</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[44:19] No.  [No.]  I wouldn’t have even have known how to do that.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[44:20] (Impersonates a male voice with an accent.)  “I am Mark Zuckerberg.”  Wear a cape, like, um (starts pointing out into the audience), Bill Gates - Bates wanted- wanted to do.</participant>
        <participant name="James Wakim">[44:25] Hi.  James Wakim.  (Inhales.)  Mark, you’ve talked a lot about your focus on the Development Platform (inhales) can you share with us three (3) Facebook apps that you would like to see that don’t yet exist today?
Pause.</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[44:38] Sure.  (Smiling and nods; Swisher laughs.)  Let’s do it.  Um (pause; looking up the his right, thinking), I think that some of the- some of the more (long pause) th-ematic things that - that people all across the world are pretty interested in (inhales; pause), um (pause), how about-  Something for sports would be - would be really interesting.  I mean, that’s not something that Facebook has built, but it would be (inhales; pause) uh- but I-  A ton of people all over the world are interested in sports.  (Inhales; pause.)  Um, maybe something more for politics.  Maybe something for religion.  I mean, we haven’t really focused on anything for helping people connect around religion, but, I mean, that’s huge thing across the world.  RIght, so (inhales) I think an application around something like that, helping people share information in that way (inhales) could represent a huge opportunity for a developer, but would also be a really interesting ways for people to connect and share information.  (Slight nodding.)</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[45:21] Yeah.  Religion-ifizes yourself.  That would be really great.  [Alright.  Thanks.]  (Looking out into the audience; point.)  That’s a great idea actually.  Right here.</participant>
        <participant name="Arthur">[45:25] Hi, I’m Arthur.  I have a question regarding you - you were talking about branding (longer pause) and what your brand was about.  And (pause) and you were saying, and congratulations to you, uh, you’ve opened your Platform to everybody.  How open are you (pause), uh, when you look at companies like Ning, which is social media, which is sharing information, which is all about opening up their Platform.  How open are you (emphasis; pause), uh, or how tight are you to your Facebook brand?
Long pause.</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[45:57] (Inhales.)  Um (pause), I mean, I (pause) I think it’s - it’s relatively open, but it’s - it’s definitely increasing as - as time goes on.  Right, so (pause) so it depends on what you are focusing on, and what we’re focusing on (pause) for the first version at least was on helping people make the same types of applications that we could internally.  Right, so complete parity there on Platform, and then making it so that people could build these types of experiences, so that people could share more types of information.  (Inhales.)  There - there are other types of things that we are definitely going to need to build into Platform before, uh, lots of other types of applications can be built, and, I mean, some of that’s going to come in the next couple of months, in the next version of Platform as Kara was talking about.  (Inhales; pause.)  And it’ll just hopefully continue for the next period of time.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[46:38] ‘kay, we are going to do quick, two (2) last questions.</participant>
        <participant name="Jim">[46:40] Hi, uh, Jim Mann with LA Times.  I’ve been on Facebook for a long time.  I have a lot of fun with it.  And I - I pay attention to my privacy settings, and I got my - my IM address up there and cell phone and stuff like that.  And I’m okay with sharing, now, with just my circle, but all these applications that ask me to (pause), you know (pause), I have to grant them access to my information.  I’m curious out of three hundred thousand (300,000) developers.  What are they doing with all that information?  Do you have policies in what they can and can’t do with it?  Do you police it, and have you - have you caught anyone doing (pause) untoward things with their information.</participant>
        <participant name="Sheryl Sandberg">[47:13] (Inhales.)  Yeah, so we, um, when you download an application, uh, you are- (pause) have the option of giving that developer your data, not all of your data, and that’s in order so that they can build the experience you want.  So some of that data is necessary so that they can do (emphasis) whatever that application is doing.  (Inhales.)  We’ve really strict policies about what (short pause) developers can do with that data.  Strict policies against- about storing, trick- strict policies about transfer that data.  (Inhales.)  Um, we have seen, you know, violations.  Those get suspended we, uh, capture the data.  Um, but for the most part it’s something that the community respects.  (Inhales.)  If you are a developer, and you are working with us we offer a really unique opportunity to you to build.  (Short pause.)  Some of our developers had, you know (short pause), small companies, most of them that they can go to.  As Mark said, it’s like millions of users overnight.  So they really have a lot of incentive (pause) to kind of play by the rules.  Particularly, around things that would, you know, knock them out of the network and not (One (1) shoulder shrug.) give the access.  (Pause.)  That’s a better long-term strategy than trying to disobey-</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[48:10] And do you actually police them?  [(Nods.)  Mhm.]  Can you actually police them?</participant>
        <participant name="Sheryl Sandberg">[48:12] We do.  And the community polices them for us.  Trust me.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[48:15] Okay.</participant>
        <participant name="Sheryl Sandberg">[48:16] We hear about everything.</participant>
        <participant name="Raul">[48:18] (Clears his throat.)  Hi, uh, I’m Raul.  Um (pause), I’ve been using Facebook for a (longer pause) for a (short pause) while now.  Probably, two - two (2) years, basically.  (Inhales.)  And, um, after, uh, the acquisition of my company I was- I joined HP, and I found Facebook to be a great tool to meet at HP.  But more to that other person’s point, after the acquisition of my company I ended up with five hundred (500) extra (air quotation) “friends.”  (Swisher laughs.)  Um, but I don’t really need know.  (Sentence said with hesitation and pausing; being polite.  Audience laughs.)  But (pause) it’s - it’s- (side smile) you know, and - and when you talk about sharing information, I’m not really sure what information I am sharing with them other than, you know, what’s on my Facebook.  (Inhales.)  Uh, you know, with the people that develop the applications and that sort of that thing.  I guess my question is (pause), is there a way you can have Friends and Acquaintances?  (Pause; Sandberg starts talking.)  Or colleagues?  Without-</participant>
        <participant name="Sheryl Sandberg">[49:06] Yeah.  There is.  Yeah - yeah, I mean it’s used-  Friend List.  We have that.
Talking over each other.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[49:08] Would that be</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[49:08] Yeah, a Friend list.</participant>
        <participant name="Raul">[49:08] Yeah, but you see that friends list-</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[49:09] (Cuts Raul off.)  Top now, Friends.  (Smiles and kind of laughs.)</participant>
        <participant name="Raul">[49:10] Top now, Friends.  Yeah, okay.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[49:12] Okay, but the idea of Facebook fatigue.  (Sandberg and Zuckerberg turn to look at Swisher.)  The idea of too many- when does it become unmanageable?  This social graph that you talk about?  Because I’m - I have hundreds of people I’m-  I don’t know who the hell they are.</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[49:21] Well, I think a lot of our job (pause) is to make it so that (pause) as people become more connected with - with more people and are sharing more information that becomes manageable.  Right?  From the flipside of sharing all of this information (pause) is that there have to be tools (pause) for people to filter and get to the information that they want.  [right]  And this is why we built Newsfeed.  Right, it’s-  I mean, there are thousands of updates-</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[49:38] (Cuts Zuckerberg off.)  Also becoming unmanageable.  I mean, again as it gets bigger, it’s become, especially when you put ads in it-  Does it - how do you-  I mean, better Search, better wha-  I mean, it does become sort of-  (Long pause; Zuckerberg starts responding.)  Enveloping.</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[49:49] Yeah.  I mean, I think - I think a lot of what - what we’re moving towards is just giving people better tools to (pause) to categorize people (Sandberg nods), categorize the types of information that they want.  But, I mean, that’s a big part of - of our job.  Is to help people (inhales) manage all of this flow of information and - and all the people they want to share this information with.</participant>
        <participant name="Raul">[50:05] Well, okay.  One (1)-  [Okay.  Very quickly.]  Yeah.  One - one (1) quick thing on that.  So you added the new Friends thing.  Where you can go and categorize your Friends and whatnot.  I still find it (pause) somewhat confusing because it still says you have six hundred (600) something, and, um, you know, on the - on the main (pause) pane.  (Inhales.)  And then the other things is if you want to have like a few Friends over or you want to send an e-mail to more than twenty (20) Friends you have to kind of make multiple Groups of Friends to do that.  Right?  To be able to manage that.  So anyways I just-</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[50:31] He wants better navigation.</participant>
        <participant name="Sheryl Sandberg">[50:32] Yeah.  And I-  So do we</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[50:33] Yeah.  Yeah.</participant>
        <participant name="Raul">[50:34] Yeah, something like that.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[50:36] And we - we- well you have to do it.

Audience starts laughing.</participant>
        <participant name="Sheryl Sandberg">[50:37] We’re working on it.
Audience laughs.  Zuckerberg and Sandberg smiling and laughing.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[50:39] We don’t really care what you want.  Um, last very, very quick question.  ‘Cause we’re exhausting this poor audience.</participant>
        <participant name="Male Audience member">[50:43] (Smiling.)  Yeah, alright.  Sorry.  This is a quick question relates very much so to the last one (1).  Triggered by.  (Inhales.)  And that is if you look at the history of the web (long pause), you know, we started off as catalogs, you know that’s what Yahoo! was.  Then we shifted to a Search based (pause) metaphor.  (Inhales; pause.)  And (pause) you guys are building, uh, kind of a new category of web page about a people as opposed to about - about subjects.  (Inhales; short pause.)  And, you know, I guess is - is, you know, all the things that you are describing are around better tools for categorizing (pause), managing, you know, this- these lists, but, uh, at some point doesn’t it flip over into becoming a much more Search metaphor.  (Inhales.)  And (pause), you know, how do you- shouldn’t you be getting ahead of the game there?
Pause.</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[51:26] Well, I mean, we’ve had Search that’s (pause) since the, um (pause), since the first version of Facebook that had almost nothing.  Right?  I mean, it didn’t [well] even have Messages.
Pause.</participant>
        <participant name="Male Audience member">[51:34] Well-  Yeah.  But - but I’m thinking, you know, just, you know-  Yes.  There’s always been Search, but, you know, Google really said, “Search is it, man.”  Bang.  Box.  So if I went to Facebook, for example, and said, “I just want to find [mm] some set of people associated with a topic.”  Or “I want to find some set of people who (pause) are associated with a company.”  Or “I wanna find, you know, some set of people who I’ve interacted within the past.”  Those are a very, very different kinds of Search than find a (emphasis) person (pause) by (emphasis) name.  (Inhales.)  And, you know, I’m just wondering how Search plays into any (emphasis) ecosystem that gets big enough that you could know about</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[52:07] (Talks over and cuts off the Audience member.)  He’s saying that you get big enough, you know, I was searching for Barry Manilow fans the other day, and he was ten (10) screens (Sandberg smiles) down (pause) my club, you know, what I mean?  I’m sorry I was.  (Zuckerberg smiling and little laugh; Sandberg smiling.)  I’ll admit it.  (Long pause.)  How do you get better as your ecosystem gets bigger?  And then let’s (pause) go on out of here.</participant>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">[52:21] (Turns to look at Sandberg.)  Yeah, I mean, that - that seems like a (turns toward Swisher) reasonable (pause), like (pause) theory on - on how that would evolve.  I think - I think as they- the amount of content gets better we have to big- wha- gets bigger we have to get better at filtering and helping people search through it.</participant>
        <participant name="Kara Swisher">[52:31] Great.  (Zuckerberg nods.)  Thanks, Mark.  So much.  I really appreciate (Audiences starts clapping) you coming.  (Reaches to shake hands with Zuckerberg.)</participant>
    </contents>
</transcript>
