<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<transcript>
    <metadata>
        <record_id>2017-053</record_id>
        <participants>Mark Zuckerberg;</participants>
        <type>social media post</type>
        <format>text</format>
        <date>2017-03-07</date>
        <source>Facebook</source>
        <title>New FB Suicide Prevention Tools</title>
        <url>https://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=10103537991633201&amp;set=a.529237706231.2034669.4&amp;type=3&amp;theater</url>
        <description>FB launching new tools to help prevent suicide on FB.</description>
    </metadata>
    <contents>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">Today we're launching new tools to help people who may be thinking of suicide, and for friends and family who want to help.

I wrote a letter on building global community a couple weeks ago, and one of the pillars of community I discussed was keeping people safe. These tools are an example of how we can help keep each other safe.

Suicide is the 2nd leading cause of death for 15-29 year olds. Preventing suicide is complicated, but experts say one of the best ways to help is if someone who is in distress hears from people who care about them.

When someone is thinking of suicide or hurting themselves, we already have tools that let friends reach out directly or report a post to us so we can help. But with billions of posts, comments and messages every day, we're limited by what people actually report to us. As a result, there have been terribly tragic events -- including suicides, some live streamed -- that might have been prevented if someone had realized what was happening earlier.

Today we're making a few changes to help do more:

- Based on feedback from experts, we’ve redesigned our suicide prevention tools and integrated them into Live video. People can now reach out to someone directly or report the stream, and the person streaming can contact a friend or a helpline.

- We're giving people the ability to chat directly with someone from organizations like Crisis Text Line, Lifeline, and the National Eating Disorder Association.

- Finally, we're testing ways to use artificial intelligence to find patterns in posts that have been reported for suicide and make it easier to identify similar posts -- even if a friend hasn't reported it. Our teams will review these posts and reach out to help if it's appropriate.

Keeping our community safe is an important part of our mission, and an important part of how we'll measure our progress going forward. There's a lot more to do here and I'm looking forward to working with all of you to do it.</participant>
    </contents>
</transcript>
