<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<transcript>
    <metadata>
        <record_id>2017-031</record_id>
        <participants>Mark Zuckerberg;</participants>
        <type>social media post</type>
        <format>text</format>
        <date>2017-01-25</date>
        <source>Facebook</source>
        <title>Explaining the Quiet Title Action</title>
        <url>https://www.facebook.com/zuck/posts/10103427714244971</url>
        <description>MZ attempts to clear up &quot;misleading stories&quot;  regarding his and MC's legal actions against Hawaiian property owners whose land they desired for a new home. </description>
    </metadata>
    <contents>
        <participant name="Mark Zuckerberg">There have been some misleading stories going around today about our plans in Hawaii, so I want to clear this up.

I posted last month about how Priscilla and I bought some land in Hawaii. We want to create a home on the island, and help preserve the wildlife and natural beauty. You can read about it here: https://www.facebook.com/zuck/posts/10103370750850071

The land is made up of a few properties. In each case, we worked with the majority owners of each property and reached a deal they thought was fair and wanted to make on their own.

As with most transactions, the majority owners have the right to sell their land if they want, but we need to make sure smaller partial owners get paid for their fair share too.

In Hawaii, this is where it gets more complicated. As part of Hawaiian history, in the mid-1800s, small parcels were granted to families, which after generations might now be split among hundreds of descendants. There aren't always clear records, and in many cases descendants who own 1/4% or 1% of a property don't even know they are entitled to anything.

To find all these partial owners so we can pay them their fair share, we filed what is called a &quot;quiet title&quot; action. For most of these folks, they will now receive money for something they never even knew they had. No one will be forced off the land.

We are working with a professor of native Hawaiian studies and long time member of this community, who is participating in this quiet title process with us. It is important to us that we respect Hawaiian history and traditions.

We love Hawaii and we want to be good members of the community and preserve the environment. We look forward to working closely with the community for years to come.</participant>
    </contents>
</transcript>
